MIGUEL U. VILLARUEL

(May 18, 1994)

Mobile: 09914086188 Viber#: 09914086188 Whatsapp#: 09452575466

Email address: migueluvillaruel@gmail.com

Professional Summary

A technology-oriented individual with attention to detail and a commitment to providing a high level of service and productivity to a company. More than 4-years of experience in Project Managing, Project Implementation and Software quality Assurance testing and 2 years Developing Automation using Selenium and Robot Framework.

Work Experiences

RPA Developer Engineer II

Nimbyx Philippines Inc. BGC Taguig (September 2023 - Present)

Experiences:

- Designing automation processes as per operational needs of organization
- Scripting and coding using Robot Framework to Resolve Automation issues
- Reviewing the code and the design and also providing expertise in the development, and integration of systems
- Configuring new automation with efficient and easily understandable Robot Framework codes
- Provides timely communication on project deliverables and quality status to the appropriate stakeholders
- Documenting the automation procedures
- . Tracks issues reported in production and ensure that they are accounted for in the next versions

Software Quality Assurance Engineer II

Nimbyx Philippines Inc. BGC Taguig (March 2023 - August 2023)

Software products: Ecommerce, HRIS, Dental Lab Management Software, Invoicing system

Product Platform: Local installed application, WEB and Mobile

Experiences:

- Prepares test automation using Robot Framework
- · Creates detailed, comprehensive, and well-structured acceptance criteria for assigned user stories
- Estimates and execute assigned testing activities
- Identifies, records, documents software bugs and issues as they arise
- Coordinates with the respective teams for bug resolution during development phase
- Provides timely communication on project deliverables and quality status to the appropriate stakeholders
- Participates in the UAT process with the Product Manager.
- Tracks issues reported in production and ensure that they are accounted for in the next versions.
- Mentors junior members of the team

Quality Assurance Analyst

Eurolink Network International Corporation Pasig, NCR (September 2022 - March 2023)

Software products: Claims Filing, Service Booking, Scheduled Billing Management and Portal, Medicine Inventory.

Product Platform: Local installed application, WEB and Mobile.

Experiences:

- Maintaining Test logs
- Automation Testing (Selenium WebDriver, Eclipse)
- Functionality Testing
- Non-functionality Testing
- UI/UX Testing
- Designing and creating test plans, test cases according to the requirements on Zephyr Scale
- Preparing test data for the procedure of testing
- Reporting bugs and issues
- Reporting test results
- Conducting Regression testing
- Load, performance and stress testing using JMeter.

Finance Officer

Thirty-one Digital Media Solutions Inc Eastwood, Quezon City (April 2022 – September 2022) Experiences:

- Managing company's accounts payables and receivables.
- Communication with clients regarding billing and payments
- Sending bills and invoices to clients
- Cross-checking invoices with payments and expenses to ensure accuracy
- Preparing Budget regularly
- Assists with reporting for the board and external financial institutions

Software Quality Assurance Engineer

Digital Spring Marketing and Advertising Inc. (Marketing arm and partner of LYKA) BGC, Taguig (March 2021 – April 2022)

Software products: Social Media Application

Product Platform: Local installed application, WEB and Mobile.

Experiences:

- Prepares test automation using Robot Framework
- Developing test plans and test cases
- Documenting and reporting software defects
- Participating in release management and conducting post validations
- Performing software manual testing
- Conducting Performance Testing
- UI/UX Testing

Project Specialist and Quality Assurance Lead

Accounting Software Consultant International Incorporated Pasig, NCR (July 2017 – March 2021)

Software products: Fully Integrated Accounting Software, Inventory Software, Payroll Software, Customer Relation Management Software and Supplier Relation Management Software. Product Platform: WEB, Mobile,

Experiences:

- Providing accurate measurements and estimates for all project's tasks.
- Automation Testing (Selenium WebDriver, Eclipse)
- Preparing Test Cases, Test Plans, Traceability Matrix and Bug report.
- Testing the functional compliance of company products.
- Accomplishing end to end Quality Assurance testing with Agile/Scrum Sprint Methodology.
- Suggesting solutions to developing problems during the project so that the correct modifications could be made.

Purchasing Officer

Fritz and Macziol Asia, Inc.

Makati, NCR (May 2015 - July 2017)

Experiences:

Increased annual revenue by recommending improvements.

Completed and mailed bills, contracts, policies, invoices, and checks.

Canvass items or materials to various suppliers to come up with the best decision on purchasing.

Educational Background:

University of the East, Manila Campus

Bachelor of Science in Business Administration Major in Financial Management